Guide to the George F. Atkinson papers, 1880-1918.
Atkinson, George F. papers, 1880-1918.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George F. Atkinson papers, 1880-1918.
21-29-103
George Francis Atkinson, 1854-1918.
6 linear ft.
Correspondence, diary, bound volume, and photograph.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence relating to the collection, classification, and study of plant specimens; recommendations for graduate students; notes on the development of botanical investigation at Cornell; and diary of a trip to Europe. Material relating to Atkinson's work at the University of North Carolina and the Agricultural Experiment Station in Auburn, Alabama.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Botanist; Professor, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence relating to the collection, classification, and study of plant specimens; recommendations for graduate students; notes on the development of botanical investigation at Cornell; and diary of a trip to Europe. Also, a bound volume of reprints, notes, and correspondence relating to Atkinson's work between 1886 and 1890 at the University of North Carolina and the Agricultural Experiment Station in Auburn, Alabama. Includes correspondence with Margaret Clay Ferguson (BS '99, Ph.D. '01). Also, platinum print photograph of students and faculty, inscribed to "Prof. George F. Atkinson with best regards of the Hindu students, Cornell University, 24 June 1907."
Index of correspondence available in accession folder.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Atkinson, George Francis, 1854-1918.; Ferguson, Margaret Clay.; Cornell University--Students.; New York State College of Agriculture. Dept. of Plant Pathology.; University of North Carolina.
Subjects:
Botany--Classification.; Botany--Research.; Plants--Collection and preservation.; Plants--Identification.; Botanists.
Places:
Europe--Description and travel.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a finding aid with an extended list of correspondents.
- Correspondence
  - 1880-1898 (Box 1)
  - 1899-1901 (Box 2)
  - Jan. 1902-Apr. 1903 (Box 3)
  - May 1903-July 1904 (Box 4)
  - Aug. 1904-Dec. 1905 (Box 5)
  - Jan. 1906-Jan. 1907 (Box 6)
  - Feb. 1907-June 1908 (Box 7)
  - July 1908-Aug. 1909 (Box 8)
  - Sept. 1909-Sept. 1910 (Box 9)
  - Oct. 1910-Oct. 1911 (Box 10)
  - Nov. 1911-Dec. 1912 (Box 11)
  - Jan. 1913-Dec. 1913 (Box 12)
  - Jan. 1914-Mar. 1915 (Box 13)
  - Apr. 1915-Dec. 1916 (Box 14)
  - Jan. 1917-Dec. 1918 (Box 15)
- Undated and printed material (Box 16)
- "Zoological publications," 1886-1890, bound volume of reprints, notes, and correspondence (Box 17)